adra.org 2018-10-08

# Privacy Policy | ADRA

## LEGAL AND PRIVACY POLICY

BY VISITING ADRA.ORG YOU ARE ACCEPTING AND CONSENTING TO THE PRACTICES DESCRIBED IN THIS LEGAL AND PRIVACY POLICY NOTICE.

All information on this Web site is copyrighted by Adventist Development and Relief Agency (ADRA®), a District of Columbia nonprofit corporation. All rights are reserved. United States copyright law protects all materials contained on this site. By using this site, you acknowledge that ADRA® owns all intellectual property rights in and to the site and its contents and that these rights are valid and protected in all forms. You may not modify, remove, delete, augment, add to, exploit, publish, transmit, participate in the transfer or sale of, and/or create derivative works from the content either in whole or in part without the express written permission of ADRA’s Marketing and Development Bureau.

### CONTROLLERS OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

Any personal information provided or to be gathered by adra.org is controlled by the Adventist Development and Relief Agency, 12501 Old Columbia Pike, Silver Spring, MD 20904. Our telephone number is 1-800-424-2372.

### COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION ABOUT SUPPORTERS

The information we gather from supporters helps us to fulfill your requests and continually improve your experience at adra.org.

We use the information to deliver publications, process donations, communicate with you about donations, update our records and generally maintain your contact details and communication records held in our database.

We also use this information to prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our Web site and to enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf.

### INFORMATION YOU GIVE US

We collect personal data using forms on our Web site. We receive and store information you enter on our Web site or give us in any other way.

Use of these forms is entirely voluntary on your part, so if you do not want us to hold any personal data about you, then please do not submit the forms. The personal data collected includes, but is not limited to, the following:

Your name  
Your address  
Your telephone number(s)  
Your email address

You can choose not to provide certain information but then you might not be able to take advantage of some of our features.

We collect this data for communication purposes. A member of our team may use it to contact you in the future. We do not collect or use this personal data for any other purpose.

Information about our supporters is an important part of our organization and we are not in the business of selling or sharing it with others. If you wish to confirm this fact, please contact our headquarters at 1-800-424-2372.

### DONOR PRIVACY POLICY

ADRA International will not share or sell a donor’s personal information collected online or offline with anyone else, nor send donor mailings on behalf of other organizations. ADRA International will only share or sell personal information once the donor has given us permission to do so.

### CHILDREN’S PRIVACY NOTICE

Our Web site is not directed to children. All offers and solicitations are meant only for adult users of this Web site. Children who visit our Web site are free to access the various features our site offers without disclosing any personal information. We do not directly solicit or knowingly collect any information directly from children. Should it ever come to our attention that a child’s personal information has in some way been provided to us, we will immediately delete that information.

### EMAIL COMMUNICATIONS

We receive and store your email address when you fill in one of our online forms and also if you subscribe direct to our newsletters or other e-publications we may offer.

Email addresses alone are never divulged by Adventist Development and Relief Agency to any third party whatsoever unless required by law.

### DONATIONS

The Adventist Development and Relief Agency (ADRA®) International provides life-changing assistance worldwide. Your contributions to ADRA® International, a tax-exempt organization under Section 501(c) (3) of the United States Internal Revenue Code are deductible for computing income and estate taxes in the United States. Donations are used to support ADRA’s® programs, and are put to work to help the needy, especially children. (Stories about people are real, but sometimes names are changed to protect their privacy.)

ADRA® endeavors to make the best use of your donation which means that at least ninety (90) percent of your donation is used for direct humanitarian services. We also recognize that your relationship with ADRA® is voluntary. As such, it is our policy that names are never sold or shared with other organizations.

### INFORMATION FROM OTHER SOURCES

Examples of information we receive from other sources include updated delivery and address information from our carriers which we use to correct our records and deliver your next communication more easily.

### COOKIES

Cookies are small amounts of data code that are transferred to a site visitor’s hard drive through their Web browser. ADRA® uses cookies only for the purposes outlined in this notice.

### SECURITY

We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software which encrypts sensitive information you input.

We transmit your entire contact details and credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during donation processing using SSL encryption.

### CONFIDENTIALITY

We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of personally identifiable supporter information. Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you.

We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to ensure that any personal data held under our control is protected from unauthorized access, unauthorized modification, unlawful destruction, accidental loss, improper use or improper disclosure. All our employees and data processors who have access to and are associated with the processing of personal data are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our site visitor’s personal data.

You can always choose not to provide personal information to us online even though it might be needed to make a donation or to subscribe to ADRA®’s publications and/or e-publications. Simply call our office at 1-800-424-2372 with your credit card details. Alternatively, you can send letters and donations to us at: ADRA®, 12501 Old Columbia Pike, Silver Spring, MD 20904.

ADRA® is providing this Web site for your information purposes only. Certain organizations may choose to link this Web site to their own Web site. Such linkage is not meant to imply that ADRA® agrees with, supports or concurs with the content such Web sites may contain. ADRA® has taken reasonably commercial steps to provide accurate content and defect-free operation of this Web site. However, ADRA® IS PROVIDING THIS SITE AND ITS CONTENTS “AS IS” WITHOUT ANY OBLIGATIONS, LIABILITIES OR WARRANTIES, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, WHATSOEVER TO ANYONE WHO CHOOSES TO ACCESS THIS WEB SITE. EACH USER EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT USE OF THIS WEB SITE AND ITS CONTENTS IS AT THE USER’S SOLE RISK. ADRA® DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THIS WEB SITE OR ANY OF ITS CONTENTS WILL BE CONTINUOUSLY AVAILABLE, ACCESSIBLE, NON-INFRINGING OR FREE OF TECHNICAL ERRORS OR VIRUSES OR ANYTHING ELSE MANIFESTING CONTAMINATING OR DESTRUCTIVE PROPERTIES, OR THAT THE INFORMATION CONTAINED IN IT IS COMPLETELY FREE OF INACCURACIES IN SPITE OF TAKING STEPS TO DO SO. ADRA® WILL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES OR INJURY (INCLUDING INDIRECT, SPECIAL, AND CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES) THAT MAY RESULT FROM THE USE OF OR INABILITY TO USE ANY PART OF THE WEB SITE, OR FROM ANYTHING SUBMITTED OR POSTED BY USERS. THE TERMS OF THIS PARAGRAPH WILL SURVIVE ANY TERMINATION OF THIS NOTICE AND WEB SITE.

This site is created and controlled under the laws of the State of Maryland which shall be the law giving effect to and interpretation of all terms and conditions hereunder. Any action pertaining to this Web site shall be in the State of Maryland with Montgomery County the venue for such action. Any person named a party to any action regarding this Web site agrees to submit to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts of the State of Maryland and of the United States of America located in the State of Maryland.

ADRA® owns the trademark for the name Adventist Development and Relief Agency as well as other trademarks. In addition to registration with the United States Patent and Trademark Office, registrations are also current or pending in various other jurisdictions. All rights in ADRA’s® trademarks are reserved by ADRA® and may not be used without permission.

Our Legal and Privacy Notice may change from time to time. You should check our Web site frequently to see recent changes.

For further information regarding this Web site or anything related to it, you may send email to the[Webmaster](mailto:info@adra.org) or write to:

ADRA®

Attention: Webmaster, Marketing and Development Bureau  
12501 Old Columbia Pike  
Silver Spring, MD 20904
